# Mark Hugh Neri

96 2nd Street Pildera 2 Pasay City

M: +63 975 492 3104 E: mh.neri@gmail.com



#### Summary

Experienced software engineer focusing on web development using .NET and Node JS

Fast learner, team-player, goal-oriented and fun-to-work-with. Highly passionate about programming and consistently learning and developing skills to be of greater value to the company and colleagues.

### Areas of Expertise

- Programming Languages: C#, JavaScript
- Web Development: ASP.NET MVC, Web (HTML and CSS), Node JS, Express JS
- Software Development: OOP, Design Patterns, Source Control (Git), Unit/Integration Testing
- Database: SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ORMs (LINQ, Entity Framework), NoSQL
- System Admin: Basic server and network configuration

# Professional Experience

### Software Engineer, Oxygen Ventures Australia

Shaw Blvd, Mandaluyong — September 2014 - February 2016

As one of Oxygen Ventures' rockstar team of developers, I was able to help develop several projects for and with top clients such as ANZ, Capitol Grand, Newsmodo and Etaskr

- ECAL-ANZ Appointment Setter Project a built-from-scratch project using ASP.NET Web API, Angular JS, PostgreSQL and Redis
- Newsmodo (newsmodo.com) new features using ASP.NET MVC with Raven DB as backend
- Capitol Grand (capitolgrand.com) WordPress theme development for a new website
- Etaskr (marketplace.kpmg.com.au) an enterprise job marketplace system using Node JS and Express JS

# Analyst Programmer, Nityo Infotech Sdn. Bhd. (Deployed to Elken Sdn. Bhd.)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia — July 2013 - August 2014

As member of the MIS Development team of one of the top MLM Corporation based in Malaysia with branches in Singapore, Brunei, Thailand, Hong Kong, Vietnam and India, I help develop and maintain several web applications both used internally by it's employees as well as customer-facing websites.

 Perform code development, updates, testing and deployment for both Intranet and customer-facing websites and applications using ASP.NET and PHP

### .NET System Specialist, Accenture

Manila, Philippines — July 2012 - July 2013

As one of the lead developers of the Accenture BPO F&A Operational Excellence Automation Team, I developed automation tools and systems for the whole Accenture Philippines BPO Finance and Accounting accounts and projects.

- Architect and lead developer of Project Hawk Eye a WPF application used by the F&A accounts
  and projects to monitor agent/processors performance and includes reports that aid future
  assessment and planning towards operational excellence
- Developed several automation tools that made client's work easier and faster using Visual Basic for Application and VB.NET

### Service Delivery Consultant, Hewlett-Packard

Manila, Philippines — December 2010 - July 2012

As owner of Workplace Services-APJ Tool and Automation Project, developed several tools that aids in execution of system administration tasks and customer-support.

- Developed a tool used by the Level 1 support team to efficiently retrieve essential information necessary for troubleshooting using VB.NET
- Developed tools for system administration such as file archiving, server monitoring and alert-system using VB Script, VB.NET and batch scripting
- Provides Level 2 support for Incident Management (HP Client Automation)

#### **Achievements**

- FY11 Q3 Best Shore Philippines Finest Gold Awardee
- Workforce Development Windows 7 Certification Trainer

### Software Development Engineer, Narra Systems LLC

Manila, Philippines — April 2010 - October 2010

One of the lead developers for a Silicon Valley-based startup building a product for Network-device testing.

- Designed Object-Oriented architecture for the backend libraries for NarraApp
- Performed code development, review and testing for the Test Managers Division of Product Development using Perl, Tcl and C++
- Performed training sessions for colleagues on the topics Perl OOP concepts, Cisco and Juniper router configuration, Perl Expect module

#### Intern, Pfizer

Manila, Philippines — May 2009 - June 2009

Designed and developed database systems for QAPD department using MS Access with reports and manuals. Created a SharePoint site for QAPD department suppliers. Exposure to Business Technology and Pfizer's CyberCafe.

### **Encoder, Green Cross**

Manila, Philippines — October 2006

Project-based encoder for sales data of the Direct Sales Department. Work output helped in sales forecast of the Direct Sales Department.

# Professional Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCTS in Windows 7, Configuration)
- ITILv3 Certification (Foundation Examination)

# Personal Projects

- Github account <a href="https://github.com/kimerran/">https://github.com/kimerran/</a>
- ASP.NET MVC Resource Routes https://github.com/kimerran/MvcResourceRoutes
- Kimeblog Blog engine using ASP.NET MVC <a href="https://github.com/kimerran/kimerran-blog">https://github.com/kimerran/kimerran-blog</a>
- Philippine Holidays (Windows Phone) <a href="http://aka.ms/philippineholidays">http://aka.ms/philippineholidays</a>

#### Education

#### **Adamson University**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering— 2005-2010

- Graduated Cum Laude
- Consistent Academic Scholar and Dean's Lister
- Recognized Student Organization's Outstanding President for 2 years
- Active officer and volunteer for National Junior Philippine Computer Society (JPCS) and Institute
  of Computer Engineers of the Philippines Student Edition (ICpEP-SE)
- Delegate for Philippine Association of Campus Student Advisers (PACSA) for 2 years

#### Organizations

- Academic Scholars Alliance of Adamson University (President, 2007-2008)
- Adamson Computer Engineering Society (President, 2008-2009)
- Junior Philippine Computer Society (AdU) (VP-External, 2009-2010)

## Microsoft Official Trainings completed

- Developing Web Applications using ASP.NET
- Writing T-SQL using SQL Server 2008
- Programming with Microsoft Visual Basic .NET

References

Available upon request.